

Roger Fos Soler

O Home: Valencia, Spain

Gender: Male **Date of birth:** 28/07/1989 **Nationality:** Spanish

ABOUT ME

Senior Full Stack Software Engineer with more than 12 years of experience, working remotely from Valencia, Spain.

I worked in a lot of startups and lately interested in fintech. I am always trying to build technology that solves business problems, rather than building technology for it's own sake. I have seen so many companies killed by it's own overengineering, so building things robust but simple and easy to maintain is key.

In my work I'm passionate and pragmatic, not bound by conventions but guided by logic. I'm open to unconventional solutions if they make sense for a particular company or situation.

I'm a programming enthusiast since the age of 12, when I started with Visual Basic and Assembly on the PIC16F84.

WORK EXPERIENCE

[01/2022 – 10/2024] Senior Full Stack Software Engineer

Myos

City: Berlin | **Country:** Germany

Myos is a fintech that gives loans using assets as collateral instead of a personal guarantee.

Responsibilities:

- Working on the existing +30 microservices and +80 repositories. (NodeJS, Typescript, PostgreSQL)
- My work here was 80% backend and 20% frontend
- Main responsible of the accounting part of the system
- Improved bookings performance by a fully rewrite of how they were executed, making the code way shorter, faster, safer and easier to understand
- Created the whole invoicing system for the company
- Being tough times for the company I ended up being the only engineer in the company during its last year. So I am in charge of infra (though it's easy with terraform already set up), fixing bugs, releasing features, downgrading when possible to reduce costs, etc.

[09/2020 – 01/2022] **Senior Software Engineer**

Lana

City: Madrid | Country: Spain

Lana is a fintech that develops solutions for GIG workers.

It has a complex microservices architecture (+35 microservices, +200 code repositories) with majority of them programmed in Golang and some on Python.

Responsibilities:

- Working on the existing microservices (Golang, Python, Vue, React, CouchDB)
- I merged 6 microservices together as they were tightly coupled

- Fully rewrote of the 6 golang microservices in one service using Python/Django in 2 months
- API for managing accounts, KYC process, etc. (Python, Django, DRF, PostgreSQL, Redis)
- Frontend and backoffice (Nuxt. Vue)

[11/2018 - 09/2020] Tech Lead, Full Stack Software Engineer

Preference

City: Valencia | Country: Spain

Preference sells solutions for the window and door industry, which includes quotation, selling, ERP, BIM and eCommerce. I worked in the eCommerce web solution, PrefWeb, where sellers or end users can personalize windows and doors in a 3D environment in the browser, where they can also place the order, create invoices, etc.

Responsibilities:

- Working on the existing PrefWeb service. (.NET MVC, .NET Core, C#, jQuery, Vue, Microsoft SQL Server)
- Designing a complete replacement for a software that runs in the factory that aids to build the different parts of the windows, communicating with the different manufacturing machines. (NodeJS, Vue, Electron)
- Introduced Jenkins, as they were deploying manually. (Jenkins)
- Introduced Git, as they were using TFS. (Git, TFS)
- Introduced better <u>e2e tests</u>, which improved speed x10. (**TestCafe**)
- Introduced <u>Vue</u>, in hopes of removing jQuery as much as possible and to better organize frontend code in components. (**Vue**)

[02/2017 - 05/2019] Tech Lead, Full Stack Software Engineer

Focusmétrica

City: Valencia | Country: Spain

Focusmétrica is a company that builds devices to track multiple variables from refrigerated trucks, from temperature to open doors, speed, gps position, etc. The main goal is to certificate that the temperature was always below a certain threshold through the supply chain.

Responsibilities:

- Build a <u>UDP server</u> where all the trucks sent all its information. Communication was encrypted by a shared key stored in the truck's device and on our servers (different for each truck). The server was a NodeJS UDP server deployed as a multi-instance, with a balancer in front. The idea was to be able to escalate to any horizontal size, and to be able to split them by feature, so you could have 5 instances for temperature data, but 20 instances for GPS positions, for example. (NodeJS, MongoDB)
- Build an <u>administration panel</u> for managing all of the trucks. It shows temperature,
 GPS history, current position in a Map, the ability to print tickets that certifies the
 temperature, etc. It also had a private <u>backoffice</u> for internal usage, like registering
 a new device. (Koa, Pug templates, Vue)
- Server management (OVH)

[11/2016 - 12/2018] Full Stack Developer

Runator

City: Valencia | Country: Spain

Runator is a runners community app where you can share your sessions from multiple running apps with your friends. It also had "global races" where people around the globe could run virtual races at the same time, with classifications, prizes, etc.

Responsibilities:

- Build a CMS to create custom landing pages for each event/race. Before of this each page was copied/pasted and modified from the previous race. (NodelS, Pug, Vue, Bootstrap)
- Build a <u>backoffice</u> for managing races. (Angular 2, NodeJS, Typescript, Webpack, Pug)
- Build a NodelS server that runs queries periodically against our databases and stores the results. Useful for statistics, product, server status, etc. (NodelS, Koa, InfluxDB)
- Build a new feed system that customized the feed for each user, instead of showing the same to all. It was a very ambitious project, at least for me. It was a nightmare to achieve good times for posting, loading the feed, etc, and it didn't work good enough to replace the old feed. We learned a few things along the path though. We discussed later that probably MongoDB was not a good db for what we wanted, at least in the way we tried to build it, which was with complex queries and aggregations. (MongoDB, Redis)
- Adding support for new apps. Runator supports a lot of apps: TomTom, Strava, Endomondo, etc. Sometimes they broke our compatibility, and sometimes a new app arises and we needed to add it. (NodeJS, Puppeteer)
- Maintenance (issues + new features) of Symfony 2 and Symfony 3 projects (Symfony 2 & 3, PHP)

[08/2015 – 12/2016] Full Stack Developer

Hooptap

City: Valencia | Country: Spain

Hooptap is a gamification service for companies looking for engaging its users. It has built-in services for creating games, points/coins system, discounts, etc.

Responsibilities:

- Build a <u>RESTful API</u> to "gamify" environments. It creates an ecosystem to give users points, achievements or levels based on complex rules like a combination of user actions, missions, etc (NodeJS, Express, Loopback, MongoDB, Cloudant, Bluemix)
- Build both an administration panel for internal usage and for our customers, to manage that gamification API (AngularJS, Webpack, Stampit)
- Create and maintain multiple custom (per-client) backends and frontends to gamify them (AngularJS, Bower, Backbone, NodeJS, Loopback). Those are special sites we created for big companies that wanted to add gamification to their ecosystem without an actual backend integration. Like for example a big supermarket in Spain wanted a site where users can introduce the codes they gave to them on each purchase. The users can put the code and see if they won any prices, see their points, play games to win more points, etc.

[01/2015 - 05/2015] **Tech Lead, Full Stack Developer**

WorldSurfTeam

City: Valencia | Country: Spain

WorldSurfTeam wanted to create a mobile application where people would be able to vot e on surf championships alongside the judges. People would be able to vote on each wave, seeing live the average score people has given to that particular wave.

Responsibilities:

- Build a <u>RESTful API</u> for all the functionality. (**PHP, Laravel, MySQL**)
- Build a webpage for voting, see the in-progress championships, waves, etc. (Angular) S, Bootstrap)

- Build a backoffice. (AngularJS, Bootstrap)
- Server management (OVH)

[06/2012 - 09/2015] Co-founder, Tech Lead, Full Stack Developer

Sixcampus

City: Valencia | **Country:** Spain

We created a platform for sharing university class notes publicly, allowing anyone to read or even commenting on each other's notes. It also allowed creating private study groups.

Responsibilities:

- Build a <u>RESTful API</u> for all the functionality. (**PHP**)
- Build a webpage, with an UI similar to dropbox/google drive (bower, bootstrap)
- Server management (AWS)

Awards:

- "Best Team", StartUPV. Valencia 2013. Prize: 500€
- "Young Developers", Fiware Smart Society Challenge. Sevilla 2014. Prize: 5000€

EDUCATION AND TRAIN-ING

[2007 – 2015] Master Degree in Telecommunications Engineering, speciality in Telematics

https://www.upv.es/ Polytechnic University of Valencia (UPV)

City: Valencia | Country: Spain |

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Spanish

Other language(s):

Valencian

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING A2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION A2 SPOKEN INTERACTION A2

English

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

My Digital Skills

Clubhouse/Shortcut | Microsoft Office | Google Docs, Sheets, Slides, etc

Backend languages and technologies

Python | Javascript, TypeScript | Golang | C#, .net | NodeJS | Bash | Nginx | AW S | Google Cloud | PHP

Software

Slack | Git | Visual Studio Code | WebStorm IDE | Jira | Goland IDE | Pycharm IDE | Docker | Jenkins | GitLab | Segment | Amplitude | Linear

Databases

Couchdb | PostgreSQL | MongoDB | Elasticsearch | Redis | SQL | MySQL | Micr osoft SQL Server

Frontend languages and technologies

Nuxt | Vue | React | HTML | Bulma, buefy | Webpack | Testcafe | CSS, SASS, LESS | Javascript, Typescript | Bootstrap | jQuery

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Hobbies

- Playing videogames, mainly Counter-Strike (+5K hours lol)
- Rubik cubes. I participated on some competitions years ago. In the 2x2 spanish ranking I am the 1000th haha.
- Piano, learning by myself for some years and 2 years of classes. But no playing for some years already. But I will be back.
- Photography, mainly macro of nature, insects, etc.
- Electronics. Love to build things, robot arms, CNCs, etc.
- Oil painting